A Guide to the Fillmore Norfleet Papers, 1940-1987
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Fillmore Norfleet Papers, 1940-1987
The Library of Virginia
33180
21 cubic feet and 4 reels of microfilm
Norfleet, Fillmore, 1903-1987
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Fillmore Norfleet, per Elizabeth Randolph Copeland Norfleet (Mrs. R. Fillmore Norfleet), Charlottesville.
Biographical Information
Robert Fillmore Norfleet (1903-1987) was born in Suffolk, Virginia, and was educated at Washington and Lee University, the University of Virginia, the University of Poitiers, and the University of Dijon. He married Elizabeth Randolph Copeland in 1938.
Norfleet taught at Episcopal High School, Suffolk High School, Furman University, and Woodberry Forest from 1934 to 1935 and from 1941 until his retirement in 1968.
An enthusiastic historian and genealogist, Norfleet collected a large quantity of material on Nansemond County and Suffolk families and places. He published several articles and books dealing with Nansemond County, including: Nansemond County, Virginia, Census of 1850 (1949); Elisha Norfleet (1800-1869), His Family and Documents (1959); Suffolk in 1843, Letters of Archibald Allen to William G. Driver (1956, reprinted 1975); Bible Records of Suffolk and Nansemond County, Virginia, together with other Statistical Data (1963); and Suffolk in Virginia c. 1795-1840, A Record of Lots, Lives, and Likenesses (1974). He also published Saint-Memin in Virginia Portraits and Biographies (1942).
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection deals with Nansemond County and Suffolk, including his substantial correspondence, primarily with Suffolk natives, about Nansemond County families and landmarks, but there is material on families related to people in this area and on the adjoining geographic areas. His files have been retained in original order, whenever possible.
These papers contain an invaluable collection of writings, remembrances, and research on Nansemond County and Suffolk. As the county records do not exist prior to 1866, these papers contain much material of significant value to researchers in the southeastern section of Virginia. Researchers are advised to thoroughly examine both the correspondence and subject files when looking for a particular family or landmark.
The papers are organized in the following series: Correspondence; Subject files; Legal documents (by type of record and chronological); printed materials (early drafts, annotated published volumes); Photographs; Maps; ca. 1 cubic foot of newspaper clippings arranged in three scrapbooks, as well as loose clippings and several complete newspapers not in the LVA collection are microfilmed and filed as Miscellaneous Reel 1049. There are also three reels of microfilm copied from eighteen smaller microfilmed items filed as Miscellaneous Reels 1050-1052.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, ca. 1940-1987., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  Filed alphabetically by correspondent (folders 1-68), followed by business correspondence (folders 69-73)
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blythe Miller Artman [Brinkley, Darden, Corbin, Artman Families (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bason-Brinkley (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Britt-Byrd (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - George L. Barton, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen Belden (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Christie Bergen (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. Hall F. Birdson (Elizabeth W.; Libber) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mrs. E. V. Blanchard (Cordelia Jones) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Marshall W. Butt (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Peter P., Esther Causey (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Anna Cahoon Coulbourne ["Cedar Vale", Cahoon Family] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mary F. Cowling (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mrs. Henry Crocker (Kacky) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mary B. Dumville (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Phyllis W. Francis (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - J. H. Granbery [Granbery Family] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. John B. Gray (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mrs. John C. Healy [Wright, Booth Families] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stuart Hall Hill [Norfleet Family] (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mildred M. Holladay [Godwin, Holladay Families] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - J (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - M. Virginia Jackson (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Mrs. Thomas C. Johnson (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - James R. Jones [Porter, Smith Families] (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Martha B. Jones (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - K (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mary C. Kendrick (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - L (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - M (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - W. E. MacClenny (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Mrs. Thelma Martineau (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Mrs. Emmet Morris [Gwin Family] (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anna Britt Myrick (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - N (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Ben E. Norfleet, M.D. [1978-80] (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Ben E. Norfleet, M.D. [1981-87] (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jose' Northfleet (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - P (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Mrs. Henley M. Parker (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - R (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Mrs. Henry A. Rawles (Brownie) [Browne Family] (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - William H. Reid (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sue Wingfield Riddick (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Mrs. Bennet W. Roberts (Elizabeth P.) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - John A. Riddick [transcripts of old letters] (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - S (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Thelma P. Savage (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Mrs. Carl Hunter Sikes (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Mrs. William S. Slusher (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Dr. Claiborne T. Smith, Jr. [1949-1956] (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Dr. Claiborne T. Smith, Jr. [1967-1986] (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - T (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - V (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - W (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Marion J. Watson (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Ruth K. Wieban [Hare, Morgan Families] (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Mrs. Sally Wolff (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - John Cooke Wyllie (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Y (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Typed and arranged chronologically (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Whittet and Shepperson [Re: Suffolk in Virginia] (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Re: Claudius J. Riddick Papers [Appraisal and Donation] (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Re: Sue Wingfield Riddick Papers (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Literary (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Dietz Printing Co. (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Series II. Subject files., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 4-17)
  - Subject Files - Part 1.
    These files are taken from a series of notebooks kept by Fillmore Norfleet on a variety of families, subjects, and places. They are arranged alphabetically and have been kept in original order. The first designation is that found on the notebook and that in brackets is the actual range found within the folder.
    - A [Adams - Allmond] (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - [Anastasia - A ?? (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - [Arnold - Austin] (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Babb - Borland [Babb - Baker] (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - [Ballard - Barber] (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - [Barcroft - Beamon] (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - [Be(a)van - Bernard] (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - [Best - Bonnewell] (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - [Booth - Borland] (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Bo - Bux [Bottinger - Bower] (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - [Brice - Brittain] (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - [Brocas - Byrd] (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Ca - Con [Cain - Causey] (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - ["Cedar Grove" - Cockle] (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - [Cofield - Cooper] (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - C II Cope - Cow [Copeland] (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - [Corbell - Cowdery] (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - [Cowling - Cowper] (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Cowper - Cutchin [Cowper] (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - [Cowper, Folder 2] (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - [Cox - Cunningham] (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - [Custis - Cypress Chapel Christian Church] (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Da - Di [Daconis - Darden] (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - [Dashiell - DeBecque] (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - [Deford - Disbrow] (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Dis - Dur [Dismal Swamp - Disosway] (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - [Dixon - Driver] (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - [Duke - Dutcher] (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - E - F [Eason - Elliott] (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - [Ellis - "Exeter"] (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - [Fanning - Fleming] (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - [Fluhart - Frost] (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Gallilee - Goodman ["Gallilee" - Glover] (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - [Godwin] (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - [Godwin, Folder 2] (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - [Gomer - Goodrich] (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Good - Gw [Goodwin - Granbery] (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - [Gray - Gwynn] (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Ha - Holl [Haile - Harper] (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - [Harrell - Harrison] (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - [Harvey - Holladay] (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Holland - Hunter [Holland - Hollowell] (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - [Holmes - Hunt] (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - [Hunter] (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - J [Innkeepers - James] (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - [Jarvis - Johnson] (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - [Jones] (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - [Jordan - Juss(e)ley] (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - K [Kearney - Kilby] (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - [King - Kondratieff] (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - L [Lafayette - Lattimer] (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - [Lawrence - Laycock] (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - [Lear - Lunan] (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Mackie - Myers [Mackie - Marriage Bonds] (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - [Marshall - Melvin] (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - [Mercer - Milners] (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - [Milteer - "Montpelier"] (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - [Morgan - Myers] (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - N [Nansemond Academy - Nimmo] (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - [Norfleet] (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - [Norfleet - Nussman] (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - O - P [Oak Island - Orange Co.] (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - [Orton - Parker] (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Pe - Pugh [Pedin - Phillips] (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - [Pierce - Pope] (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - [Porter - Prentis] (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - [Pruden - Punkinshire] (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Queen - Rustin [Queen - Randolph] (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - [Ratcliff - Rhodes] (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - [Richards - Riddick] (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - [Rising Sun Tavern - Rutter] (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Sack Point - Smallwood [Sack Point - Schools] (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - [Scott - Shelton] (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - [Shepherd - Smallwood] (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Smith - Sunbury [Smith - "Soldier's Hope"] (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - [South Quay - Sprye] (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - [Stallings - Sunbury] (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - S [Sumner] (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - [Swan - Syme] (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - T - V [Taberer - Taylor] (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - [Teare - Turner] (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - [Turrentine - Vestry Book] (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Wa - Wi [Wakefield - Weatherly] (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - [Webb - Wells] (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - [West - Wiggins] (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - [Wilder - William and Mary (Nansemond Alumni) (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Will - Z [Williams - Withers] (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - [Woddrop - Woory] (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - [Wrenn - Zeluff] (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Subject Files - Part 2.
    The following files are created from a variety of arranged and partially arranged materials found in the Fillmore Norfleet Papers. The arrangement is artificial and designed to reflect a common theme or subject. Several broad categories were chosen and material was arranged alphabetically by subject within the broad categories as follows: Individual/Families; Bible Records; Cemeteries; Churches; Diaries, Letters, Account Books; Land Records; Lots; Marriage Records; Military Records; Mutual Assurance Society; Newspapers; Places; Wills and Abstracts of Legal Records; John R. Kilby Papers; Webb-Prentis Papers; Miscellaneous; and Bibliography.
    - Individuals/Families: David Baker (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Individuals/Families: Baker [by Simmons Jones Baker] (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Individuals/Families: Ballard - Sumner Families [includes Baker, Nosworthy Families] (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Individuals/Families: Ballentine Family (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Individuals/Families: Bankhead-Formicola Families (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Individuals/Families: Barradale Family (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Individuals/Families: Beamon Family (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Individuals/Families: John Blake [Burgess 1655-56, 1666] (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Individuals/Families: Brewer Family (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Individuals/Families: Brewer - Cooper - Vardaman Families (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Individuals/Families: Byrd Family (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Individuals/Families: Carter Family (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Individuals/Families: Cathan Family (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Individuals/Families: Thomas Abthorpe Cooper [1776-1849] (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Individuals/Families: Copeland Family (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Individuals/Families: Copeland/Barbour/Nixon/Jones Families (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Individuals/Families: Hannah Lee Corbin (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Individuals/Families: Willis Cowling (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Individuals/Families: Cowper Family (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Individuals/Families: Denby/Milner Families (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Individuals/Families: Denson Family (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Individuals/Families: Digges/Riddick/Sumner Families (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Individuals/Families: Eley Family (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Individuals/Families: Everett Family (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Individuals/Families: Garrison Family [includes Hus(s)ley, Wyatt Families] (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Individuals/Families: Godwin Family (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Individuals/Families: Goodman Family (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - Individuals/Families: Granbery Family (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - Individuals/Families: Harrell - Holland Families (Box 7, Folder 191)
    - Individuals/Families: Holland Family (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - Individuals/Families: Holland Family [by Lee Pretlow Holland] (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Individuals/Families: Lowe Jackson (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - Individuals/Families: Jones Family (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - Individuals/Families: Jones Family [includes James R. Jones pedigree] (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Individuals/Families: Cecely Jordan (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Individuals/Families: Jordan Family (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - Individuals/Families: Jordan/Scott Families (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - Individuals/Families: Barnaby Kearney [burgess 1684] (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Individuals/Families: Knott Family (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - Individuals/Families: Lee Family [by Lee Pretlow Holland] (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - Individuals/Families: Lewis Littlepage (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Individuals/Families: Milo Mahan (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Individuals/Families: Louisa Cheves McCord (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Individuals/Families: Milner/Norfleet Families [Scottish connections] (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Individuals/Families: Milteer Family (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - Individuals/Families: Minor Family (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Individuals/Families: Christopher Norfleet (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - Individuals/Families: John Norfleet of Kent (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Individuals/Families: Thomas Norfleet of Kent (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet, His Life [additional material] (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Family [Folder 1] (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Family [Folder 2] (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Family [Deeds, Folder 3] (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Family [Folder 4] (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Family [Land Tax Lists] (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [entries from Vestry Book] (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Elisha and Hamlin L. Norfleet] (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [W. A. Graham Clark Notes] (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Stuart Hall Hill Notes] (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Mrs. Frank Hough Notes] (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Dr. C. T. Smith, Jr. Notes] (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Introductory material; Aaron - Abraham] (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Christopher I - Edward III] (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Edward IV - John] (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Joseph I - Richard Henry] (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - Individuals/Families: Norfleet Family [Riddick - Wright] (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - Individuals/Families: Parker Family (Box 8, Folder 233)
    - Individuals/Families: Parker/Ballard/Smith/Custis Families (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Individuals/Families: Perinor (Box 8, Folder 235)
    - Individuals/Families: Phillips Familly (Box 8, Folder 236)
    - Individuals/Families: Lewis F. Powell (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - Individuals/Families: Anne Whiting Pryor (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - Individuals/Families: Pugh Family (Box 8, Folder 239)
    - Individuals/Families: Quiney-Burbarge Families (Box 8, Folder 240)
    - Individuals/Families: John Randolph of Roanoke (Box 8, Folder 241)
    - Individuals/Families: Nancy Randolph (Box 8, Folder 242)
    - Individuals/Families: Randolph Family (Box 8, Folder 243)
    - Individuals/Families: Rawls Family (Box 8, Folder 244)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Notes [Re: Cynthia, Josiah, Henry, James, William Sumner, Mills, Lemuel Riddick (Box 8, Folder 245)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family [Folder 1] (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family [Folder 2] (Box 8, Folder 247)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family [Folder 3] (Box 8, Folder 248)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family [Kendrick's Notes] (Box 8, Folder 249)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family (Box 8, Folder 250)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family [Abstracts From Published Materials] (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family (Box 9, Folder 252)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Individuals/Families: Riddick Family (Box 9, Folder 254)
    - Individuals/Families: Rolfe Family (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - Individuals/Families: Toby Smith [Burgess 1642-43, 1649] (Box 9, Folder 256)
    - Individuals/Families: Smith Family (Box 9, Folder 257)
    - Individuals/Families: Sumner Family (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - Individuals/Families: Charles L. Swett (Box 9, Folder 259)
    - Individuals/Families: Syme Family [includes "Rocky Mills"] (Box 9, Folder 260)
    - Individuals/Families: Syme Family (Box 9, Folder 261)
    - Individuals/Families: Henry St. George Tucker (Box 9, Folder 262)
    - Individuals/Families: Nat Turner (Box 9, Folder 263)
    - Individuals/Families: Pasco Turner (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Individuals/Families: University of Virginia [Biographical Sketches] (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - Individuals/Families: Vickery Family [includes Felix T. Sharles, Norfolk Herald abstracts] (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Individuals/Families: Joseph P. Webb [Society of Cincinnati Papers] (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Individuals/Families: Webb Family (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - Individuals/Families: Wilkinson Family (Box 9, Folder 269)
    - Individuals/Families: Wilson/Jordan/Riddick Families (Box 9, Folder 270)
    - Individuals/Families: Wimberly Family (Box 9, Folder 271)
    - Individuals/Families: Wright/Sumner/Lawrence Families [Mrs. Virginia Phillips notes, correspondence] (Box 9, Folder 272)
    - Individuals/Families: George Wythe (Box 9, Folder 273)
  - Subject Files - Part 3.
    The arrangement and description of the following is that of Fillmore Norfleet. Some of the items appear to have been considered for publication or are very early stages of items that were eventually published. They cover a broad spectrum of families and are filed at the end of the Subject Files, Individuals/Families.
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Airs - Brown] (Box 9, Folder 274)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Browne - Custis] (Box 9, Folder 275)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Darden - King] (Box 9, Folder 276)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Lassiter - Prentis] (Box 9, Folder 277)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Rawles - Riddick] (Box 9, Folder 278)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families [Saunders - Wright] (Box 9, Folder 279)
    - Individuals/Families: Nansemond County Families (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - Individuals/Families: Biographies of Suffolk People (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - Individuals/Families: Biographies to Accompany Map [to be edited] (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - Individuals/Families: Biographies to Accompany Map [to be edited] (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Individuals/Families: Some Suffolkians and Their Occupations (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - Individuals/Families: Isle of Wight Co. Families [J. B. Boddie abstracts] (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - Individuals/Families: Immigrant Ancestors [Abstracts from Virkus] (Box 9, Folder 286)
  - Subject Files - Part 4.
    The following subject files consist of the research or notes of individuals other than Fillmore Norfleet, but found in his papers as separately ?? entities. They have been separated here, keeping their original arrangement as being filed by the name of the compiler.
    - Individuals/Families: William H. Bason Notes [Lee-Pipkin-Goodman-Harrell Families] (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - Individuals/Families: Mary B. Dumville Notes [Bunting, Dumville, Norfleet, Smith Families] (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - Individuals/Families: William March Notes [Riddick Family] (Box 10, Folder 289)
    - Individuals/Families: Elisha Norfleet Notes (Box 10, Folder 290)
    - Individuals/Families: Frank E. Parker Notes (Box 10, Folder 291)
    - Individuals/Families: Frank E. Parker Collection [Record Abstracts, Harrell, Parker Families] (Box 10, Folder 292)
    - Individuals/Families: Claudius Riddick Notes (Box 10, Folder 293)
    - Individuals/Families: Claudius J. Riddick Mss. Collection (Box 10, Folder 294)
    - Individuals/Families: C. T. Smith Notes (Box 10, Folder 295)
    - Individuals/Families: Marion Joyner Watson Notes (Box 10, Folder 296)
    - Individuals/Families: Elizabeth B. Wingo Notes [Ballentine, Cawson Families] (Box 10, Folder 297)
    - Individuals/Families: Wrenn-Woodward Notes [Cole, Cowling, Duke, Felton, Gregory, Harrell, Parker, Pugh, Riddick Families] (Box 10, Folder 298)
    - Bible Records: Rawles, Murdaugh, Jordan, Harrell, Blackwell, Arthur, Norfleet, Daughtrey-Langston, Holland (Box 10, Folder 299)
    - Bible Records: Smith, Jordan, Rawls, Minton (Box 10, Folder 300)
    - Bible Records: Elisha Norfleet, Edward Norfleet, Jackson Brinkley, Thomas Norfleet, Hersey V. Knight (Box 10, Folder 301)
    - Bible Records: Riddick, Ballard, Harrell, Moore (Box 10, Folder 302)
    - Bible Records: Riddick, Holland, Holladay, Honey (Box 10, Folder 303)
    - Bible Records: Allen, Brothers, Cahoon, Crump, Darden, Eley, Finney, Godwin, Kelly, Pinner, Prentis, Riddick (Box 10, Folder 304)
    - Bible Records: [to be added to those published] Allen, Darden, Daughtrey-Langston, Harrell, Lawrence, March, Norfleet, Riddick, Royster, Wright-Chastain (Box 10, Folder 305)
    - Cemeteries: Cedar Hill Cemetery, Tombstone Inscriptions (Box 10, Folder 306)
    - Cemeteries: Cedar Hill Cemetery, Tombstone Inscriptions (Box 10, Folder 307)
    - Cemeteries: Cemetery Records (Box 10, Folder 308)